So fight. Just fight.
What are you doing?
I mean you're clearly
muttering to yourself
while staring at your reflection.
But how come?
Ya just that bored? Or?
Hey. You said, "So fight.
Just fight." Right?
But when you say, "so fight, just fight,"
who is it you're wanting to fight?
I noticed that you said "fight" twice.
Does that mean you'll fight two fights?
Or one fight with two rounds?
Your silence isn't helping your case.
I mean why would you talk to yourself
but then ignore another person?
This doesn't seem normal at all to me.
I've never chatted up my mirror before.
But on a brighter note,
I'm loving your new hairstyle!
Yeah. The disheveled look
makes a statement.
It's like you can't be
bothered to deal with it,
'cause you're busy working so hard...
What did you come here to do?
What do you mean?
I came here to talk.
The first time we met,
we spent all night talking
about Titans. Remember?
Though looking back,
I guess you just listened
as I rambled about my research.
I had faith in you.
I trusted that you would
never sacrifice Historia.
Eren. It's been a year now.
I haven't seen you since you
picked up our whole ship.
I look forward to working beside you.
Too bad.
You won't be working with Eren directly.
This meeting is as far
as we're willing to go.
More than enough for me.
This is an auspicious day.
The port's complete at last.
And we're about to welcome
our first foreign visitors.
From the sole nation
that's friendly to Paradis.
Hizuru.
Their Special Envoy is Kiyomi Azumabito.
Do you happen to
recognize this family crest?
That shape.
Yeah. You should
show it to them.
You think?
But Mom told me that
I should keep it a secret.
You showed it to me
back when we were just kids.
This could be the whole reason
she gave it to you. Go on.
Before she died, my mom gave me this mark
to match one she had herself.
And she asked me to pass
it down to my own children.
A noble deed, befitting your lineage.
Over a century ago, Hizuru's shogun
was an ally of the Eldian Empire.
We Azumabitos trace our
lineage back to his son,
who was on good terms with King Fritz,
and often visited here.
After the Great Titan War,
our once-proud nation
was left defeated and in disarray.
And amidst the chaos and confusion,
a child fathered by the Shogun's heir
was somehow left behind on this island.
You are the only direct
descendant of the family
that once led our nation.
Put simply, you are Hizuru's hope.
They keep saying
the word "nation."
I still don't understand it.
What matters is that this
gives us leverage over Hizuru.
Unless it's a trap, that is.
Right. Perhaps we
should ask Yelena's opinion.
No! That's exactly
what they want us to do.
We're sure of one thing at least.
In this world that our
new port has connected us to,
we may as well be a tottering
child, learning to walk.
For now, let's keep quiet
and learn what we can from our guests.
Hey. So that symbol.
Why'd you only show it to Eren?
You've always worn that wristwrap.
I've never seen you take it off.
That's because, um...
Hey. You're in a good mood.
Of course I am!
Seems our ancestors were friends.
They've left us both with
heavy burdens to bear.
But I couldn't have asked for
a more perfect match than you.
This is a historic day
for both our nations.
And it's worth noting that
this day would never have come
if not for the man
who brought us together.
I'm speaking, of course, of Zeke Jaeger.
We conversed with him in secret,
and before he would agree
to facilitate this meeting,
he negotiated with us
on behalf of your island.
We discussed more than Lady Mikasa.
First of all.
Take a look at this.
That's...!
That's odd.
Do you recognize this?
It's top secret in Marley.
Well, as you may know,
this omni-directional mobility gear
is an anti-Titan weapon made in Paradis.
This piece doesn't belong to Marley.
I procured it myself.
Please consider it a gift.
I ought to mention though,
it does need a special type
of fuel to operate.
It's exceedingly rare.
They're calling it
"Iceburst Stone."
It's only ever been mined in Paradis,
so very little is known about it.
That said, you should be
able to find traces of it
inside that apparatus.
Zeke Jaeger's proposal
was that we ally with
and assist Paradis in exchange
for access to a resource
that could return our nation
to its former glory.
It's a rather tempting offer.
Thus, while we're aware
that he made this offer
without surveying your reserves,
we suspect that in this modern era,
a treasure like iceburst stone
could change the world
and generate a fortune in the process.
Sounds like that's Hizuru's real hope.
Yelena did say that
negotiations would go well
because the Azumabitos
are money grubbers.
This is a dangerous island to visit.
I doubt anyone would take the risk
if there weren't money to be made.
Hold on. So Zeke Jaeger
asked you to "assist us"?
What would you assist us with?
As I'm sure you're aware,
he's concocted a plan to
protect Eldia and the world.
We're here because
this plan can only succeed
with Hizuru's assistance.
It calls for a three-point
course of action
which would allow you
to defend yourselves
with your so-called "Rumbling."
This would begin with
a test run of the Rumbling.
You would unleash a fraction
of the Titans in your walls.
Enough to display their
destructive potential
for all the world to see.
That will buy you time with which to
modernize and strengthen your army,
so as to render the Rumbling unnecessary.
You're a hundred years behind
the rest of the world.
Hizuru will help you catch up.
Until then, you must be
able to shake the earth
by maintaining the Founding Titan
and having a Titan of royal blood.
That's the third point of this plan.
Zeke will pass on the
Beast Titan to an individual
who has royal blood.
And that person must spend
the 13 years they'll have left
bearing as many children as possible.
Even if we get advanced weapons,
will we really stop needing the Rumbling?
If we choose to rely on it,
we'll have to continue the practice
of Titan inheritance for generations.
I see how it could protect us
for the time being,
but is that enough of an excuse for us
to push this problem
onto our descendants?
Of course it isn't. And yet...
I understand. And I'm ready.
If the Rumbling is
essential to our survival,
I'll do my part.
I'm willing to inherit the
Beast Titan from Zeke Jaeger.
Historia.
If Zeke's plan is to buy our salvation
at the price of broken walls,
trampled lands,
and children bred to be
slaughtered like livestock,
then I say he can go to hell
and take his sick little plan with him.
Staking our survival on
the threat of the Rumbling
is a dangerous move.
So before we commit to it,
we should try to find another way.
Let's use what time we have
to look at our options.
I felt the same sense of
urgency that you did, Eren.
That said, I still don't get
why you acted on your own.
You pushed our island into a war
we aren't ready to fight.
Why? Did you stop
caring about Historia?
I've taken the War Hammer Titan's power.
Its hardening ability
allows me to build
structures from thin air
or carve them into earth and stone.
Which means you can never build a prison
deep or strong enough
to hold me in against my will.
I can leave this cell anytime I want.
And since I have the Founding Titan,
you can't kill me.
You might threaten to kill Zeke,
but that's not a real option, either.
So, tell me. Hange.
Is there anything you actually can do?
If you know something I don't,
then let's hear it.
If you've got something up your sleeve,
then tell me what it is!
Hands off, you pervert!
Ever the rebellious teen, huh?
Grow up! Idiot.
Erwin.
This is the one time
you bet on the wrong horse.
Why did you ever think that
I could be Commander?
Why don't you come in, Historia?
You need to take better care of yourself.
If no one else'll say it then I will.
We should've stuck with our plan
and fed Zeke to Historia
as soon as he got to the island.
We'd all be safer if we had.
Ha! But we let her do as she
pleased and so she got pregnant.
Then again, what did we expect?
I mean she's an upjumped bastard
who's queen in name alone.
Hey! Quit it.
The queen has every right
to choose a partner for herself.
He's been checked out, so we
know he's not anyone's lackey.
He's someone she knows.
Apparently, they grew up
in the same area.
As a kid, he'd throw rocks at the queen
because she wouldn't leave her farm.
He must've wanted her to notice him.
He said that when she
opened her orphanage,
he started working there out of guilt.
I believe him.
He worked hard and kept his
head down for years there.
She approached him, in the end.
I don't give a damn
about their love story!
Look. What I'm concerned about
is why the girl selfishly decided to
get herself knocked up when she did!
And I think I've got a good guess.
Somebody told her that it would stop us
from turning her into a Titan.
I bet it was that turncoat, Yelena.
The giantess is nuts,
but she's smart, too,
and that's a dangerous combination.
"Just put a baby in the queen
and Zeke Jaeger gets
to live another day!"
Roeg. You've had too much.
If we were smart, we'd still do it.
Turn her into a Titan whether
she's pregnant or not.
That would probably kill the child.
And if miscarrying kills
the queen, too, we're doomed.
It's too risky.
Giving birth poses a threat
to her life as it is.
That's a perfectly sound argument
that could bring our country to ruin.
Hey! Marleyan!
Get us another bottle!
As you wish, sir.
Greiz.
Nicolo.
You should recommend this one.
Hey! Is this really
something they needed us to do?
Nope! They'd've
hired someone...
If that idiot hadn't opened his
mouth and volunteered our help.
"We can develop the
island and our muscles
at the same time," my ass.
Well we don't have much else to do,
except wait for Hizuru's answer.
Uh-huh. Hopefully,
with their help,
we can win some friends in this world.
It might be a long shot,
but it could be an
alternative to the Rumbling.
And that could save
Historia from suffering.
Hey!
Phew! It can't be easy,
working your butts off
when it's this hot out.
Yeah, well.
We have to be here to
watch over this moron, right?
You brats got taller.
It's like you're sprouting up
just to spite me.
Hear anything from Hizuru yet?
That's why we're here.
The Azumabitos replied.
What'd they say?
It's no good.
Hizuru either can't or
won't help us with this.
Makes sense.
Hizuru has a monopoly
on any resources that we
want to export right now,
so why would they ever help us
trade with other countries?
From what I hear,
the world's major powers
want Paradis to be the root of all evil.
We're the shared foe that
helps brings them together.
Their hatred for us
promotes global stability.
Then... do we have to
rely on the Rumbling?
Do we have no choice
but to sacrifice Historia?
That's right.
So what? The world's
decided that we're devils,
regardless of what our intentions are?
They can't want us to repeat the past,
so why won't they consider peace?
Probably 'cause they don't know better.
They don't know anything about
us and that makes them afraid.
I agree. Our neighbors
across the sea
won't trust people whose
faces they've never seen.
So let's sail out and meet 'em!
If they don't know anything about us,
then we'll just have to teach them!
That's what we Scouts always do, right?
So the plan is to infiltrate Marley
and set up a base there, huh?
I like it.
Hange has a plan
for everything, am I right?
It's exciting.
We'll all get to chow down
on food from a distant land.
Yeah. Wonder what
we should pack.
Hope that foreign food
doesn't give us the runs.
We'll need to pack some
antacids, a toothbrush,
and a taste of home.
Did you even hear Hange's plan?
If we can just find a way
to convince the world
that all we want is peace,
maybe our situation'll change.
If we only had a little more time left.
My time will be up
in just over five years.
We need to make a decision soon.
About who to give my Titan to.
I think it should be me.
No. Not an option.
We don't even know if Ackermanns're
able to turn into Titans.
And even if you could, Hizuru
would be furious about it.
You're their long-lost heir, remember?
It can't be you for more
reasons than I can count.
Who do you think it should be?
This guy.
First of all, I'm a whole lot
smarter than Eren.
We'd replace this suicidal
maniac with a gifted leader
who shows good judgment
in all situations.
A rare specimen who can perform
whatever duty is required.
I don't much like
getting his hand-me-downs,
but hey, I'm the best
candidate we've got.
Sure, except we
can't afford to lose someone
that valuable after just 13 years, moron.
Ha?
You should aim to become
the regiment's next commander.
I'll inherit Eren's Titan myself.
Yeah. That should work. Right?
Conny.
No, that won't work at all.
You're way too much of an idiot.
Eh?
Use your head, Conny.
This is a really important duty.
We can't entrust it to someone
who's slow, like you.
Huh?
Ya really get my goat sometimes.
I'll inherit it, okay?
I'm an experienced veteran,
and I've proven that I'm
someone you can rely on.
By process of elimination,
you've gotta use me.
You guys...
I get that I have to, but still,
I really don't wanna.
Sasha. Wait.
You're not making any sense.
Huh?
I mean, you know.
We can't give his Titan to an idiot.
You just told me that.
But think.
You're more of an idiot
than me, which means,
you just contradicted yourself, right?
Huh?
I'm not planning on
handing it down to any of you.
Why not?
Because you're important to me.
More than anyone else.
I hope...
you'll live long lives.
Ha?! Hold on!
What are you turning red for?
The hell kinda mood are
you trying to set here?
Sorry.
Jean. It's just the sunset.
That's what's making our faces red.
Oh. Right. That makes sense.
There's nothing to be done, then.
So Pyxis detained the volunteers?
Such a strong-arm tactic.
It's hard to believe he'd go that far.
They had built good working relationships
with a lot of us Scouts,
so our regiment wasn't
notified in advance.
That said, I doubt Pyxis had much choice,
'cause until we understand
Zeke's real intentions,
his presence here
puts us in a tough spot.
I wonder what made Eren
decide to go with his plan.
Him and Zeke must've talked,
but what was said...
Well, no one knows except for them.
Hey. Did that guy look like Eren
when you all saw him?
'Cause if you ask me, that wasn't Eren.
And if whoever that was
is capable of picking his
half-brother over us, then...
If he is, then what?
Then I say we'll need to be prepared to
cut him down ourselves if necessary...
I won't let you!
Are you taking their side,
too, Mikasa? Come on.
I don't think it'll come to that.
Eren cares about us
more than anyone else.
Everyone here should know that.
Maybe that's why he's become so combative
towards anyone who isn't one of us.
It's because his feelings are so strong.
No, that isn't it.
He's always seen your strength,
but the Eren that we used to know
would still try to keep you
away from the front lines.
But he used you in that battle.
Sent Armin to destroy that port.
He called the rest of us important, too,
and he used us just the same.
But maybe that's
just because he trusts us.
I mean, if we hadn't helped him,
his plan would've failed.
Yeah, and Sasha would be alive right now.
Hey. What do you think Eren did
when I told him she had died?
Do you think he cried?
Or showed some regret maybe?
Conny. Stop.
The bastard laughed.
I wonder what part of our
friend's death that it was
that he found so damn amusing.
Why don't you explain, Mikasa?
Why did Eren start laughing?
You know everything
about him. Right?
We need to talk to him.
Just Eren, Mikasa, and me.
We'll give him a chance
to explain his goal.
Are you sure that'll help?
Tell me, what if his goals
are the same as Zeke's?
The volunteers gave us Titan serum,
so we have a choice now.
Wait, what are you saying?
We can choose to turn someone
who we can trust into a Titan,
and then have them inherit
the Founder from Eren.
Good stuff.
Gabi and Falco escape from their cell.
They wander, lost and alone,
through the wilderness,
till they find themselves
saved by one of the devils
they've been taught to hate.
Next episode: "Deceiver."